one of the people who I reached out to
help me communicate the idea was asking
this for I'm her from her like a week
she was like wait it sounds like
communism could you explain how it is it
is it was like well this idea is the
best of capitalism and communism without
the downside clearly in my
in part that draws people in but then
when you look at communism throughout
history and the atrocities that happen I
mean I some degree understand how they
happen like I don't understand why Pol
Pot kill all the intellectuals like if
you knew how to read if you wore glasses
you removed like that to me is so I mean
clearly unethical but like how does that
help you at all how does it help and
also in communist and one of the
favorite things on there like and cab
and calm sight that I'm part of on
Facebook is like the idea that communist
like communist equal starvation it's
like okay not necessarily but I
understand we actually kind of do suck
at central planning as a species and so
to me explaining that the system is like
the best of capitalism communism was
like well what what is the good part of
communism I think there's a lot of good
I think that people helping one another
and giving kind of what you can is a
positive but then the downside is pretty
big and the idea that communism goes
through this in-between period that's
never been gotten out of we're like okay
well this this elite group will take
ownership I guess well like wheel
century essentially plan everything and
we'll be like the new elite but like
will give the power back when it's time
and of course spoiler alert they never
do and what I'm proposing has not about
because there is no us in them there is
no hierarchy there is no central system
that's like we're gonna take over power
and then and then give it out the
closest thing we do have that is we can
only be as transparent and democratic as
technology allow I was well we create
that technology and so that is a bit of
a gray area where it's like I'm still
worried I can't be honest and
transparent about like every thought in
my head
clearly I'm trying but it's not it's
maybe not the best communicator but that
there is no transition period it's just
then there is no central planning in the
same way like we're not taking down all
of the economy and then being like oh
great how what do we do so how many
loaves of bread is it that we need in
who who who grows the wheat up
it's it's the opposite it's we live
within a capitalist society which is
also like and she was like well they
much and so explained to communism part
like the best part of calm you know how
it is the best part of communism she's
like well great but what's the best part
of capitalism like that's so much harder
for me to answer and I think it's
similar to like I was raised Christian
and it very much influences Who I am but
at the same time very critical of it and
in a way that I'm not critical about the
religions because I wasn't raised that
way and at the same time like I live in
a very Christian society like when we
celebrate Christmas and Easter and so
it's it's similar to that where it's
like capitalism is our water that we
live in it's what like this idea that
we're not going to have innovation if
innovation isn't done for money I get it
it's so pervasive and I'm like oh how
are people gonna innovate I'm like
people aren't innovating for money very
few people want money they want what
money will get them they want connection
they want they want um power they want
like there's certain things that people
people want and that's there's not
necessarily anything inherently wrong
with that like the fact we exist along
the spectrum of cooperative to
competitive nothing wrong about the
issue as capitalism only kind of rewards
the uber competitive and everyone else
is not able to be out and not like so
anyway so having what is the best side
of capitalism that it has I do think it
has innovation when you unleash the
genius in people it's its own reward to
create like scientists don't actually
the ones that are the reason people get
into science is because they want that
aha moment they want to like years of
putting in all of this time to get that
aha moment is what's worth it
not necessarily the paycheck they need
the paycheck but it's not um it's not
the incentive and I would say the same
is true for inventions and art and
everything else I mean do people only do
art because they could make it rich and
and it's big one day I don't think so I
think it's something that calls from
with and it makes at least the good ones
right where it doesn't matter if you
have like ten fans
million fans if it's Colleen from video
and so yeah the best part the capitalism
is very ad hoc solutions and uber
competitive and communism like uber
cooperative like to the point of forcing
people to cooperate and is central
planning and I think we suck at both of
those things and so we need the best
world roads and this person also
introduced me to someone called Mac
Ridley who wrote a book who have not
read yet because I'm just introduced to
it today but I did look up one of his
speeches he went even had a talk at
Google and him was listening to that
did I say the name Matt Ridley it's like
a evolution of everything and how this
concept of like what I'm gonna call them
cuz he doesn't call that but like
top-down approaches versus bottom-up
approaches and I'm very much about the
bottom-up approaches and he talks about
evolution which is my my background so
I'm just getting into all of that
capitalism and communism how he talks
about how innovation is very bottom up
and we're like a bunch of people created
lightbulb at the same time it was like
ripe for the creation and evolution and
calculus and the theory of relativity
and all these things where even if the
person had died who was the founder of
it who we attribute to being the the
person who discovered it we'd still have
it we just wouldn't know like we'd still
know the DNA is a double helix even if
let's say Walla secret that's not right
I should know this I'm a geneticist an
ecologist and I just heard it too
whatever that's not gonna come to me if
it's not there now but the two people
who discovered the double helix and I
know there was another person the exact
same time actually who also was
discovering double helix
how many wait there wouldn't there would
still be the the innovation just on that
way and how we kind of like remix stuff
and I'm like yeah that's what I'm all
about that's kind of the system he's
kind of talking about but we don't
necessarily in the system we suck of the
system and I think we can have both we
can have like the internet is all
information and that's awesome but it's
also over well
chaotic and we can't trust it so how do
we create the system where we can trust
it i think wikipedia is similar to that
like it's like okay at least we can see
down how much we trust it and even
better I think if Wikipedia if the
policies were crowd-sourced the same as
articles were crowd-sourced then we
could the people the crowd could come up
with solutions to things like a
corporation or a celebrity doing their
own page right I don't know if the
solution to that is what about you
someone in the crowd knows what the
solution to that is and when things are
done in a transparent democratic manner
everyone can have access to that
information and so yeah do you think we
can have the best of capitalism
communism my worry is that like my what
I do have the gift I have in this world
to give part of it is based on my
personality I'm a Barry you spent a lot
of my life with this struggle between
these two dichotomies right of masculine
and feminine and I mean I'm a middle
child don't think that's a dichotomy no
it sounds like I'm not the oldest no not
the youngest and I'm like the funny
thing is the more I embrace my dichotomy
the more I do go if I don't go inside
I'm like I'm like to you hip you for the
cabin to capitalist for the hippies like
I don't think I'm too careless for
anyone now
I very much I can see the beautiful
parts of capitalism I can I do
understand economics for them I think
the regular population you can just
ignore it you can't ignore supply and
demand that's what happens in Venezuela
I can't why don't you say that word and
I know I get that country that's going
to horrible times and I feel like I'm
making a joke because I can't say the
freakin word and that is a central
planning nightmare because you have
someone at the top who thinks they have
all of the solutions and the ego
involved and like no no like people I'm
sorry I know you're talking about
finally it's like oh don't people are
starving we have failed and I'd say
that's the the highest point of failure
in society but then we also are like
look at all these communist countries
failing her socialist countries when
capitalism is also failing in a very
different way it's destroying our planet
in our social structure and we're in it
so we can't really see that it's Bailey
and it's like we are Rome collapsing we
can and our scientists are saying it and
even our politicians understand that
they need to do something but they're
not really designed to change the system
because they are only in for four years
and some of these things are ten-year
plans right like we need to be able to
have every day people agreeing with
something because they helped create it
and even if they didn't help create it
they were invited to like you coulda if
you'd heard about this six months ago
you could have come help come with our
climate change policy whatever it is but
when you don't have that central
centrally plan like I think my dad's
libertarian the happiness few laws as
possible especially when we already have
the greater law system right and that's
the beauty of greater losses them having
as few laws as possible where they're
like just very obvious like don't kill
people you know like maybe Ten
Commandment type stuff but not the ten
commandments because those are not okay
but they don't kill part of it die down
with no rape and murder and violence of
any kind and no something else to talk
about but I wanted to connect our God so
10 minutes but am I to say hotel bed but
that that's what I was that my I'm able
to see the dichotomy like I'm able to
see the beauty in both and bring them
together and where there's a trade-off
have as little trade-off as possible um
that also to some degree means I'm like
oh god I gotta convince the Communists
that like capitalism is still a little
bit okay and I've to convince the
capitalist a little bit okay especially
when there is these like uber words like
is this calm you know which I'm reading
a tone of voice you may have been like
Louis is communism so I love the
communist that having that that yeah
that I have to kind of convince both
people it's I got to convince the
hippies the capitalism or like business
is important and became this the
business people that the environment is
important and that's daunting so I'm
just not I'm just
signing my people and that's the beauty
is that we're gonna start from a culture
of cooperation so people like I don't
understand I asked the question like
innovation like how are people gonna
innovate it's like okay you just you do
realize you just signed on to the right
quasi strangers strangers thoughts on
how to change the world without any talk
of payment like you like you're not
being incentivized with money you're
being incentivized because you have a
calling to write and you want to whether
this thing speaks to her or not is a
whole other story but like that's what
we're tapping into that be genius try
not to clear my camera bet I clear my
throat a lot this part of the way that
tapping into the people that are over
cooperative instead of the uber
competitive ones means we're gonna have
a culture of like yeah give what you can
give what you got money-wise for it
there's a specific fee for that so that
we can function as a society it's taking
away a lot of the issues that come with
nonprofits and such you know they caught
like every new idea needs marketing and
finance and it's a big problem it's like
you have a best idea and you're not
getting a note to the people you want to
get it out to it's gonna fail that's
marketing you have the best idea and
just not understand money and and
therefore not be selling it even at
breakeven points and then you're not the
finances aren't taking care of right you
need enough money to start it be enough
money to keep it going and you need to
be fiscally responsible so hopefully
you're spending less money and therefore
profit and combining those so that every
new idea is not like we have a funding
source we don't have to keep writing
grants we don't have to keep going to
our membership and asking for new
donations like Wikipedia does without
transparency they're doing just fine
they get what we're money than they
actually need but like all of that like
I'm like I'm not giving in to Wikipedia
even though I use them all the time
because I know that they're I think I
know that they're doing proper like
they're not transparent I don't know
what
honey they're a non-profit but they
aren't democratic they aren't owned by
all of us I
so finding like here if we find 1
million people it doesn't have to start
with 1 million but I love the idea of a
million has a million people signing on
hand to give 10 dollars a month and in
the beginning that doesn't make sense so
it's ten dollars just ten dollars right
like a million people to give to give
ten dollars and then it's like but these
people get the bit later on we're gonna
give ten dollars a month each it's a
voluntary tax and that's the difference
everything is voluntary everything
within it is okay you're giving of
yourself how you want to give yourself
right you don't have to do no one's
forcing anyone to give ten dollars a
month it's like hey does it excite you
to give $10 a month to change the world
it's the state of the world maybe make
you a little anxious and upset I would
give him ten dollars a month towards
actual solutions help alleviate that for
you because it would for me and yeah 1
million people giving $10 money so we
have 10 million dollars a month to focus
that money towards creating technology
because technology's the most bang for a
buck in the beginning it's where we can
bring our knowledge together and our
data to have it be usable and where we
can give it away for for free once it's
made if we vote to do that right where
something's gonna help you about eat
healthier or live better lives we can
choose to give that to beyond our
membership it's harder to do with a
brick-and-mortar store right like but
like just feed the masses just give the
give people housing it it's like wait
who's paying for that whatever it's
there just take it it's like that's not
that doesn't really work our system
doesn't like hurt people I love people
who have like a social justice warrior
heart and it's just and it's like yes
but it doesn't work that way like where
does the food come from the next time
then if you're just co-opting the food
like you can't go in and take the means
of production when you don't know how to
run the means of production and it's not
really about the golden whip like you
can't just go in and take over Amazon
but you
ten bankrupt Amazon you can create a
system where the employees of the thing
we create are paid ethically where
instead of these two forces that are in
opposition of each other of like we want
stuff delivered overnight it's like they
want to make money we can decide okay
well what's the ethical what is a proper
delivery time four to six weeks like it
used to be when you order thing by mail
maybe not overnight same-day delivery
also possibly not especially for able to
track around data and able to oh you're
probably about to run out of toilet
paper would you like to add that to the
list for adding that to the list for you
maybe you picked some off at Costco and
you don't need are this like you know
what I mean like it could be an
intelligent system or it's both being
updated by what we throw out it's been
updated by what with by it's been
updated so that we then know when it
makes sense to start our own means of
production now by taking them over but
by creating them finding them right like
right now it doesn't make sense to have
a toilet paper company even as ethical
as it could be
what we want is like once people's like
hey you wanna buy talkable from us we
can have a better yet toilet paper
producing like tapes your paper and just
makes toilet paper right that's in like
every neighborhood give your paper here
doesn't have to ship away right hey
creating toilet paper and if we actually
have enough paper for that my kids here
and you know I asked for this but it's
been 18 minutes I'm gonna go